Meredith Moore

113 N. Patrick St #1, Alexandria, VA 22314 (703) 401-0470 • contact@meredith-moore.com

Writing samples: <u>meredith-moore.com</u>

Professional Summary

Environmental advocate, policy analyst and science writer with nine years of experience researching, developing, and communicating science-based policy to the public and decision-makers.

Author of qualitative and quantitative research reports that have significantly shifted legislative and regulatory outcomes and expanded public understanding of federal fishery management and endangered species protections.

Research scientist with a graduate degree in Astronomy with an elective focus on terrestrial atmospheres, including courses in atmospheric chemistry, radiative processes, and remote observing, with additional graduate level coursework in science journalism.

Experience

Senior Associate, Federal Fisheries Policy (2013 - present)

The Pew Charitable Trusts, 901 E St. NW, 10th floor, Washington, DC 20004

Researched, analyzed, developed, and influenced federal laws and regulations impacting the management of wild ocean fish populations in the United States. Led internal analysis, external outreach, and coalition activities in response to proposed revisions to key federal regulations on fisheries sustainability. Successfully delayed regressive legislation while developing and advocating a platform for ecosystem-based fisheries management.

Ensured the scientific rigor of our work through literature reviews, outreach to and collaboration with scientists and federal agency officials. Led the scoping and development of a new scientific research grant on rebuilding depleted fish populations. Prepared public comments, legislative and regulatory text, congressional testimony, policy statements, fact sheets, and internal policy analyses. Represented Pew through congressional lobbying, at professional conferences, and at federal agency meetings and workshops.

Senior Research and Policy Analyst (2010 - 2013)

Food & Water Watch, 1616 P St. NW, Suite 300, Washington, DC 20036

Conducted in-depth research on U.S. fisheries management and aquaculture policies for a national consumer-advocacy nonprofit organization. Combined federal policy analysis with academic literature research to author lengthy investigative reports into catch shares fishery management; these reports were actively used by congressional offices and coalition partners to support legislation. Researched and authored dozens of fact sheets, regulatory comments, and briefs on federal fisheries policy and aquaculture.

Handled numerous media requests for major and regional newspapers and radio broadcasts. Tracked and prioritized responses to national, international, and academic developments in fisheries management, aquaculture, and seafood safety. Lobbied Congress on

fisheries issues and collaborated with fishermen coalitions. Supervised six interns on numerous research and outreach projects.

Scientific Integrity Analyst (2007-2009)

Union of Concerned Scientists, 1825 K. St NW, Suite 800, Washington, DC, 20006

Independently analyzed allegations of political interference in federal scientific programs at a national science-based environmental nonprofit. Investigations combined primary interviews with agency and academic scientists with thorough research of available literature and reports. Wrote and edited numerous web-based and print analyses, public comments, and congressional testimonies.

Represented the organization at professional conferences, in coalitions, on the Hill, in briefings and in meetings with high-level federal employees. Served as a media spokesperson, which included pitching stories to the press. Supervised five interns and authored a curriculum guide for advanced high school and undergraduate teachers.

Notably, exposed interference by the Office of the Vice President and the White House Council of Economic Advisers to delay a rule that would minimize fatal ship collisions with the critically endangered North Atlantic right whale. This investigation generated a letter from the House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform and media coverage by three major sources (The Associated Press, The New York Times and The Washington Post). Shortly thereafter, the rule to protect the whales was released without significant modification.

Education

Master of Science in Astronomy, December 2005, GPA: 3.6

University of Maryland, College Park, MD

Elective focus on terrestrial atmospheres and satellite observation.

Graduate-level coursework in science journalism

Bachelor of Science in Physics (cum laude), May 2003, GPA: 3.7

University of Georgia, Athens, GA

Foundation Fellow (University of Georgia's premier academic scholarship program)

University of Georgia Dean's List (4 semesters) and Presidential Scholar (1 semester)

Selected Publications (Portfolio at: <u>meredith-moore.com</u>)

The Pew Charitable Trusts. Comments on Proposed Revisions to National Standards 1, 3, and 7. June 30, 2015.

The Pew Charitable Trusts. Statement before the U.S. Senate Committee on Commerce, Science and Transportation, Subcommittee on Oceans, Atmosphere, Fisheries, and Coast Guard. Hearing on Southeast Regional Perspectives on Magnuson-Stevens Act Reauthorization. Nov 14, 2013.

Food & Water Watch. Fish, Inc. 2011.

Union of Concerned Scientists. Scientific Integrity Curriculum Guide.

McCarthy, Meredith. Numerical Modeling of Gas in Spiral Arms with a Simplified HI Cooling Function. Graduate project for a Masters in Astronomy. University of Maryland, 2005.